Hello friends, I am Krishna, welcome to
today's informative video in which
I am talking about daily news analysis and
benefits with financial advisors.
Every morning at 8:00 AM, we bring this special
program to you
where we
tell you every update of the insurance and investment industry
which is important for you to know.  In today's
video we are talking about ICICI Bank
which is more of an insurance company
and less of a bank.  What was lost and what was gained?
Many things are
changing in the ICICI Lambar company and the ICICI Bank company.  So the
reason why it is more important for you to understand this video is
that ICICI Bank is
working in the market with very good service
and it is
my job to tell you what opportunities are there for you in it.  There
may be some things I
tell you in this that you should not do.  Let
me tell you some things that you should do.
So let us know in this video
why ICICI Bank is less of a bank and more of an insurance company for you?  What has this
bank lost and what has it gained?  And
what is important to you?  Will tell in this video.
Before starting the video,
we have already achieved a challenge of 365 days.
Which we did between 5 June 204 and 4 June 2025.
In which we
gave you 65 plus courses worth more than ₹90,000.
If you want to access them again,
you can download our app Krishna Lodhal accdemy from Google Play Store or Apple App Store and subscribe to them again.
And we also organised an event on June 8th.
If you want to access its recording also,
you will get it on the app.  Do
n't forget to subscribe and press the bell icon because
you will keep getting these videos every day for 365 days
and today is the 50th day of this video.
So let's start the video.  So
friends, some questions may be in your mind.
Like whether ICICI LB is deliberately
withdrawing from its motor insurance business.
ICICI LB has reduced insurance.   The
biggest update from ICICI for you is
that it has planned to make some changes in its insurance business
and
despite the growth of 32% in health insurance, the loss in ICICI's insurance business
domain has increased.
Apart from that, why did the company suddenly turn away from crop insurance
?  Why has that company
directly withdrawn from crop insurance?
I will tell you this also.  Are electric vehicles
becoming a new threat to insurance companies?  We will
discuss about this.  ICSL LBAT has
reduced the insurance and we understand it in detail.  Is
commercial vehicle insurance a
loss-making proposition now?  So we will try to understand this also
and in the end I will
tell you what is the takeaway for you
from this video which is important for growing your video.
ICICI LBT has
reduced motor and commercial insurance.
What is the reason?  Heavy pressure on premium prices
and declining profitability.  Any company
can make its business sustainable only when
profitability is maintained in that business
and scalability is high.  Even though this
business has a high potential for scalability,
ICICI is reporting
that its profitability has decreased.
Third party premium in commercial vehicles has remained
stable for the last four to five years.
Meaning, revenue did not increase, but the risk
remains and the risk remains.  ICICI
LBAT said that now we will do only that much
business there which gives us profit.
Apart from that, if the business is not giving profit, then they will
leave that business.  As an Advisor has
some messages for you.  You can shift the
customer towards health home travel insurance instead of motor insurance.
Ok?  ICICI LBT did a
great job in motor insurance.
But now he himself is saying
that he no longer sees that level of scope in it.
Whereas I
partially agree with this.  Health insurance is
second with 32% growth but still the risk has increased.
Now the claim ratio has increased to 74%.
But the company claims that it is still manageable,
which I don't find to be true.
All of you have to make the client focus on renewal because if
renewal does not happen then it will be a problem for you as well as for the
company.  In a better plan,
you should provide add-on riders which will make it
easier to cover the claim.  If you learn this thing
then you
can provide good service to the customers.  Third, why distance from crop insurance
?  ICICI LMB earlier used to take up to 17%
share in crop insurance.  Now he has only
5% stake in the field of crop insurance.  The
reason is the tender based low price system
in which there is more risk rather than profit.
That is why he feels that
he should not show much interest in crop insurance
because it has a tender based system
and the tender is obtained only after investing a lot of money.
You know very well about corruption in India.
Promote crop insurance only
when there is a specific demand from the government or clients.
Ok?  Promote crop insurance only
This is his.  Now there was
heavy pressure in prying also.  Ok?  There was
heavy pressure in Priing in fire insurance.  But
after 17% renewal growth in April, it was back in the do
mode.  Because the heat
is increasing in India and if we talk about metro cities, the
risk of fire is
increasing there.  So now the company will go
back to writing selective fire insurance and
you can get good deals on fire insurance from the company.
So I am
trying to tell you everything that can make your business
scalable.  After that,
you can start selling fire insurance by explaining it to SME warehouse owners.
Anyone who has a godown, a shop, or is
doing small business may suffer losses.
If there is a fire then there is a
small premium involved.  But
a big market is open for you.  EV which
we are calling electrical vehicle.
One in every four EV two-wheelers and 17% of EV
cars are insured by ICI.   That
means, if we talk about the EV sector, then
taking 17% market stake in the beginning is a
big thing.
High claims are not trending in EVs in India yet.
EV is new right now.  There are no batteries.   It is
possible that in future the claims may increase
but you can target the EV owners by
packing up the policy with extra benefits along with the eco-friendly tag, you
can make a combo that eco-
friendly policy, okay now here 50% of the
companies are still spending beyond the limit
but now the regulator is in action
and is looking for equal opportunity.
Now EOM will bring discipline in the market as per the guidelines.
Ok?  And after that
if we move a little further then there is a
high commission of 32% in health insurance and
commission in housing finance health insurance is up
to 15% in retail individual as per IRDA rules.  Now there are direct benefits for you, there has been a
growth of 32% in health insurance.  Higher
commission is available in housing finance.  Ok
?  After that, as per IRDA, the
individual also gets up to 15% commission
in retail.  And the company has registered 32% growth in this sector
in quarter one of FI26.
Meaning you can get the opportunity to earn more sales and more commission
in this business.
If we talk about fire, the renewal
growth is 17%.  Now it can be up to 16.5%.   But there is
no need to worry.
With ICICI LBAT,
you can focus on all other insurances except crop insurance.
Because ICICI,
which is a lobby, is working in different sectors
but is working more in the EV sector.
EV Sector Fire
Property Marine You know you can work more in these things.
And thirdly the
segment balance in motor insurance ICICI LBAT is
trading down in motor insurance.  So
ICICI Bank has already done a lot of motor insurance.
Maybe the bank feels that something new should be
tried now.  That's why he's coming to EV.
So if you move ahead with the current trend of the company, then
you will benefit and the company will also
benefit.  The client will also benefit.   There are
many more benefits for you directly.
Where Pay U Know Motor Insurance
By balancing the segment you get OD Part Own Damage Commission
which varies from 15% to 17% on Car Bike OD.
So you should focus on all these things and
think about expanding your business.
Look, if you sell only one product,
your demand in the market will decrease.  Even
if it is not less, you will
not be able to expand much.  Now you have to make this choice.
You have to select, check
whether you want to diversify your work
or want to work in very limited things.
You are right on both counts.
Even if you want to work in just one or two product segments, you are
fine.  You will be able to work with very targeted laser focus.
But if you have to follow the
market trend then
people want a lot of things.
If you don't have a lot of things, your
scope will be limited.  You have to decide.
Please let us know how you liked this video by commenting.
You should focus on social media video marketing.  Join Social Media Package 3 6
9 You can join for a period of 12 months.
Where we will do the work of branding for you on YouTube, Facebook,
Lindin, Twitter, Telegram, Instagram and
WhatsApp channels
and will try to make you a branded advisor in a year.
What will happen with this?  If you are currently dependent on commission income, then
after 1 year you will have at
least 10 other sources of passive income
generated.  Every Friday
we have a Wonder Webinar.  Which is a 1
hour power packed live session that I take.
Every Friday evening from 8:30 to 9:00,
in this 1 hour between 8:30 to 9:30 I
teach you trending skills in the market.
Like Artificial Intelligence, at this time there
is a lot of scope for Artificial Intelligence.  If you want to grow and increase the speed of your work,
then
you should learn AI.  By joining this masterclass,
you can increase the speed of your work by learning AI.
You can register immediately by adjusting ₹199 and clicking on this QR code.
I allow only 100 people in the class.
So that questions and answers are asked from them
and you are taught in a good manner.
If you are serious about
moving ahead in this business and learning AI,
register now.  You will find the registration link
in the video description and the pin
in the comment.  And if you have any
question, feedback, suggestion or complaint,
you will see two numbers below this video.
You can get detailed information by contacting our board line number.
Thank you so much for watching.  Maid.